macomb.edu 2017-05-19

# Macomb Community College - Privacy Policy

The following policy applies to users of the Macomb Community College websites and is intended to identify the types of information Macomb gathers from users and explain how that information is used.

**Information Collected when You Visit the Macomb Community College Websites**

You can explore most of the Macomb Community College (“MCC”) websites without revealing any personal information. MCC may, however, collect general information about the way in which you use our websites, including, but not limited to, the time and duration of your visit, type of web browser used, the operating system/ platform you are using, your IP address, the websites from which you linked to MCC, and your CPU speed. MCC also may note whether and how you use MCC’s websites by recording site traffic patterns and clickstreams. MCC may also perform (or have third parties perform) analyses of visitors' behavior, and may share aggregated, anonymous data with sponsors and advertisers.  

**Information Collected When You E-mail Macomb Community College or Complete a Transaction**

During your visit to our websites, you may send e-mail to MCC. Your e-mail address and the contents of your message will be collected. The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats included in the message.

In order to register for classes, purchase goods or services, apply for employment or complete other transactions with the College, you may be asked to voluntarily provide personal information. Any personal information you choose to provide MCC will only be used to conduct official MCC business. The personal information you provide may be used by MCC (or third parties engaged by us) to: (1) customize the advertising and the content that you see, (2) fulfill your requests for products and services, (3) contact you, (4) conduct research, (5) respond to subpoenas, court orders or legal process, or (6) establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims. MCC will not sell, rent, loan, trade or lease personal information collected on this site. Except for children who register for MCC education or enrichment programs, MCC does not knowingly collect or use personal information of children. Users are cautioned, however, that the collection of personal information submitted in e-mail will be treated as though an adult submitted it.

**Cookies**

Cookies are small amounts of data that MCC’s websites may place on your computer’s hard drive. A cookie file contains unique information that MCC’s websites can use to track such things as the password you create to access any MCC site, lists of webpages you have visited, the date when you last looked at a specific webpage, or to identify your session on our websites. A cookie file allows MCC’s websites to recognize you as you click through pages on our site and when you later revisit our site. MCC’s websites uses cookies to "remember" your preferences, and to record your browsing behavior on our websites. Although you can prevent MCC’s websites from placing cookies on your hard drive, there may be some features of our websites that will not be available to you and some webpages may not display properly if you disable cookies.

**Links**

MCC websites may include links to other websites. We do not control the privacy policies of the destination sites. Once you leave MCC servers (you can check where you are by checking the URL in the location bar on your browser), use of any information you provide is governed by the privacy policy of the operator of the site you are visiting. That policy may differ from ours. If you can't find the privacy policy of any of these sites via a link from the site's homepage, you should contact the manager of that site for more information. MCC is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of websites other than the MCC websites.

**Confidentiality and Integrity of Personal Information**

MCC is strongly committed to protecting personal information collected through its websites against unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Consequently, MCC limits employee access to personal information collected through its websites to only those employees who need access to the information in the performance of their official duties. Employees who have access to this information follow appropriate procedures in connection with any disclosures of personal information.

In addition, MCC has implemented procedures to safeguard the integrity of its information technology assets, including, but not limited to, authentication, authorization, monitoring, auditing, and encryption. These security procedures have been integrated into the design, implementation, and day-to-day operations of MCC’s websites as part of our continuing commitment to the security of electronic content as well as the electronic transmission of information.

Although MCC employs security that we believe to be appropriate to protect your personal information, we do not guarantee that our security precautions will protect against, and we expressly disclaim any liability for, any loss, misuse, or alteration of your personal information.

**Changes to MCC Privacy Policy**

MCC may update this policy at any time. We will notify you about significant changes in the way we treat personal information by sending a notice to the email address that you have provided us or by placing a prominent notice on our website.

**Contact Information**

You may contact us at:

Macomb Community College  
14500 E. 12 Mile Road  
Warren, Michigan 48088  
Phone: 586.445.7314  
Email: [webinfo@macomb.edu](mailto:webinfo@macomb.edu)

Approved by President's Council  
May 24, 2016
